<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:mathml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
  <title>Структура книги</title>

  <para>Книга разбита на десять глав и три приложения. Главы затрагивают
  следующие вопросы:</para>

  <para>Chapter 1, <emphasis>Установка</emphasis>, описывается процесс
  установки Extbase и Fluid. Для усовершенствования процесса разработи
  расширений, даются советы по настройке сред разработки и отладке.</para>

  <para>Глава 2, <emphasis>Основные принципы</emphasis>, начинается с обзора
  концепций объектно ориентированного программирования, так как они особенно
  важны при работе с Extbase. Затем мы углубляемся в Предметно ориентированное
  проектирование (Domain-Driven Design), парадигма программирования,
  оптимально поддерживаемая в Extbase. После этого даются сведения о шаблоне
  разработки Модель-Представление-Диспетчер (MVC: Model-View-Controller),
  ясляющегося технической основой каждого расширения Extbase. И наконец
  объясняется принцип разработки через тестирование (TDD: Test-Driven
  Development).</para>

  <para>Глава 3, <emphasis>Journey through the Blog Example</emphasis>, should
  give you a feeling how the concepts from chapter 2 were implemented in
  Extbase. Based on a given example extension we explain how a blog posting is
  created and goes through the different system stages until it is
  shown.</para>

  <para>В главе 4, <emphasis>Creating a first extension</emphasis>, we show
  you a minimal extension. With this extension, data is managed through the
  TYPO3 backend, and displayed in the Frontend.</para>

  <para>Глава 5, <emphasis>Modelling the Domain</emphasis>, shows
  Domain-Driven Design with a practical example. It shows how a model can be
  planned and implemented.</para>

  <para>If the domain model is finished, the necessary TYPO3 infrastructure
  must be created: Database tables and backend editing forms. The relevant
  information is explained in chapter 6, <emphasis>setting up the persistence
  layer</emphasis>.</para>

  <para>After chapters 5 and 6 have explained the model layer in detail, we
  now focus on the application flow of the extension in chapter 7,
  <emphasis>controlling the flow with controllers</emphasis>. These are
  implemented in the controller layer.</para>

  <para>Now, only the output layer of the extension is missing, the so-called
  <emphasis>view</emphasis>. In chapter 8, <emphasis>styling the output with
  Fluid</emphasis>, Fluid is explained in detail and its functionalities are
  shown with several examples. At the end of the chapter, the explained
  functionalities are combined and demonstrated at the example
  extension.</para>

  <para>Глава 9, <emphasis>internationalization, validation and
  security</emphasis> deals with advanced topics and tasks. This includes the
  multilingual capabilities of extensions, the validation of data and the
  handling of security aspects.</para>

  <para>Глава 10, <emphasis>outlook</emphasis>, gives a glimpse into code
  which is currently being developed. The focus lies on the kickstarter and
  the use of Extbase in the TYPO3 Backend. Additionally, this chapter shows
  you parts of FLOW3 and explains how Extbase Extensions can be ported to
  TYPO3 v5.</para>

  <para>Extbase mostly uses the conventions of FLOW3. In <emphasis>Appendix A,
  Coding Guidelines</emphasis>, they are summarized.</para>

  <para>Appendix B <emphasis>Reference of Extbase</emphasis> contains an
  overview about important Extbase concepts and an alphabetical listing of the
  API.</para>

  <para>In Appendix C, <emphasis>Reference of Fluid</emphasis>, you can find a
  reference of all standard Fluid ViewHelpers and the API which is needed to
  create own ViewHelpers.</para>
</section>
